<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.zzf.rikki.idea</id>
    <name>Rikki Coding Agent</name>
    <vendor email="zhengzhengfeng@outlook.com" url="https://github.com/Creeper5261/Rikki">Creeper5261</vendor>

    <idea-version since-build="241"/>

    <description><![CDATA[
        Rikki is a lightweight AI coding assistant for JetBrains IDEs.<br>
        No backend server required - connects directly to LLM APIs.<br>
        Cross-IDE support: capabilities degrade gracefully based on IDE features.<br><br>

        <b>Chat Agent</b><br>
        An AI panel that can read files, write and edit code, run terminal commands,
        and perform Git operations. High-risk commands (file deletion, force-push, etc.)
        always pause for your explicit Approve / Skip confirmation before executing.<br><br>

        <b>Inline TAB Completion</b><br>
        Ghost-text suggestions appear as you type; press TAB to accept.<br>
        <ul>
            <li><b>FIM mode</b> (Fill-In-Middle) for DeepSeek and Ollama - sends prefix + suffix
                directly to the model's dedicated completions endpoint for accurate in-place suggestions.</li>
            <li><b>Chat-format fallback</b> for OpenAI, Gemini, Moonshot, and other providers.</li>
            <li>Completion can use a <b>different provider, model, and API key</b> than the chat agent
                - ideal for using a fast/cheap model for completions and a powerful model for chat.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>Multi-Provider Support</b><br>
        Built-in presets for DeepSeek, OpenAI (GPT), Anthropic (Claude), Google Gemini,
        Moonshot / Kimi, Ollama (local, no key required), and fully custom endpoints.<br>
        Each provider stores its own API key - switching provider automatically loads the correct key.<br><br>

        <b>Setup</b><br>
        Open <b>Settings -> Tools -> Rikki Coding Agent</b>, choose your provider, enter the API key,
        and select a model. For local use, choose Ollama - no API key needed.
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <b>0.1.1</b> - Cross-IDE compatibility and capability-gated IDE tools
        <ul>
            <li>Removed hard Java module dependency so the plugin can install on non-Java JetBrains IDEs</li>
            <li>IDE-native tools are now capability-gated and gracefully fall back to bash workflows</li>
            <li>Build/test default path is bash; run/debug/status still use IDE bridge when available</li>
            <li>Bash tool now supports shell auto-fallback across bash, PowerShell, and cmd</li>
            <li>Addresses issue #1: remove Java hard dependency for PyCharm/PhpStorm usage</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="com.zzf.rikki.idea.settings.RikkiSettings"/>
        <applicationConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            instance="com.zzf.rikki.idea.settings.RikkiSettingsConfigurable"
            id="com.zzf.rikki.idea.settings.RikkiSettingsConfigurable"
            displayName="Rikki Coding Agent"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="com.zzf.rikki.idea.IdeBridgeServer"/>
        <toolWindow id="Rikki" anchor="right"
                    icon="/icons/toolWindowRikki.svg"
                    factoryClass="com.zzf.rikki.idea.ChatToolWindowFactory"/>
        <inline.completion.provider
            implementation="com.zzf.rikki.idea.completion.RikkiInlineCompletionProvider"
            order="last"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="Rikki.TriggerCompletion"
                class="com.zzf.rikki.idea.completion.RikkiTriggerCompletionAction"
                text="Trigger Rikki AI Completion"
                description="Manually trigger Rikki inline AI completion at cursor">
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt BACK_SLASH"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
